Bojan Angjelkoski

Principal Engineer | Technical Lead | MSc in Software Engineering

Skopje, Macedonia | Belgrade, Serbia • <u>bangjelkoskii@gmail.com</u> • <u>https://bangjelkoski.com</u>

EXPERIENCE

Principal Engineer | Technical Lead

Oct 2019 - Present

Injective Labs | Remote

Software architecture for various applications, managing and leading a team of developers, protocol design, building SDKs for external developers, maintaining documentation and open source projects, innovating new and bleeding edge technologies, etc

- Participated in the design and development of Injective and all of its components,
- Team lead of the Frontend Engineering team and responsible for all external integrations, developer experience, and documentation,
- Conceptualized, prototyped, and built a fully functional dApp for cryptocurrency trading within two months. The founders managed to increase the initial proposed funding by 50% from the investors because of the result.

Technologies used: Nuxt.js | Vue.js | TaliwindCss | Webpack | Blockchain | Go | Web3

Software Engineer Aug 2018 - Dec 2021

World Trade Organisation | Remote

Full stack development on multiple internal applications for the need of the World Trade Organization.

- Built a new application from scratch by designing the infrastructure, database models, codebase architecture, and view models for cross-team usage within the WTO.
- Increased the performance and efficiency of existing applications by up to 10 times by optimizing the codebase and replacing old technologies with new ones. Reduced the cost of operation and infrastructure by proposing new methods of storing data and code,
- Refactored all legacy applications to use the latest principles and coding standards for easier maintenance and new features building,

<u>Technologies used:</u> Nuxt.js | Vue.js | TaliwindCss | Webpack | Larevel | MongoDB | SQL

Full Stack Developer Oct 2017 - Aug 2018

Nulisec | Remote

Full development cycle (concept, requirements definition, development, design, deployment, and maintenance) for a native (desktop/mobile/web) eCommerce app for connecting European wholesalers and retailers.

- Grew sales by 18% and new registrations by 30% by redesigning and restructuring our old marketplace into a SPA.
- Implemented UI and UX improvements based on A\B testing that resulted in an increase in all of our KPIs.
- Developed SaaS web application for Czech retailers to digitalize their eCommerce business. Transformed more than 90 businesses, making 1000+ orders while also reaching more than €200k of GMV per month.
- Integrated support for ERP systems for Czech businesses to exchange data with our application that allowed syncing 200k+ products, stocks, orders, and everything related to their business easily.
- Refactored legacy code into a tested and properly architectured application which led to more than 70% fewer bugs reported by our customers/showed in our error logs.

<u>Technologies used:</u> Nuxt.js | Vue.js | Node.js | Microservices | TaliwindCss | Scss | Laravel | Inertia | Webpack | REST APIs AWS | ElasticSearch | Redis

Full Stack Developer Feb 2014 - Oct 2017

NG Solutions GmbH | Remote

- Implemented a front-end client for rapidly building restaurant websites. The project exceeded the target growth by 15% a month, launching a total of 80+ restaurant websites within the first 3 months of the initial launch.
- Built, maintained, and optimized a SaaS for managing restaurants in Switzerland. Over 25 restaurants were receiving more than 400 reservations/per week.

Technologies used: JavaScript | jQuery | React | Boostrap | Scss | Laravel | Node js | REST APIs

SKILLS

HTML | CSS | Sass | Tailwind | JavaScript | TypeScript | ES6 | Node | Vue | Vuex | Nuxt | React | Redux | Webpack PHP | Laravel | MySQL | MongoDB | Git | TDD | DDD | UI | UX | CI | CD | AWS | Docker | JAM Stack Serverless Architecture | REST APIs | Accessibility | Agile | System Design | OOP | Design Patterns | Remote Work

EDUCATION

University of Belgrade | Master of Science in Software Engineering

Sept 2018 - Oct 2021

University of Belgrade | Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering and Computer Science

Oct 2013 - Mar 2018

PROJECTS

Redesign of the CommerceLayer.io website

Dec 2019

• Full website redesign findings from customer segmentation and competitive research while also taking developer experience and modern design into consideration which led to leads increase by 70% and sales increase by 25%.

A platform for interactive learning - CodeCademy

Feb 2018

• Developed web application in JavaScript for my university to help students learn web development by watching lessons and working on interactive tasks and projects; used by more than 100 students each year.

Property management and vacation rental app - Booksi

Jun 2017

• Founded, developed, and launched an app that allows people to build instant websites for renting out their properties. After 300+ customers, it's still one of the most popular software of its type having a stellar 5.00 stars from customers.

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Facilitated two 3-day workshops in Serbia for junior developers to increase their knowledge and gain more experience by building small but challenging projects.
- Held a lecture to fellow students about the benefits of writing clean and understandable code.
- Coached 20+ interns about writing clean code, following the SOLID design principles and practical examples of design patterns, and using them in improving our code quality.
- Taught junior developers at a local workshop about the JAM stack and how they can utilize this approach to build modern web applications.
- Streaming live coding sessions for other developers while working on side projects.
- Guided 10+ junior developers into getting their first job/internship as developers.
- Participated in regional and international programming/mathematics competitions.

SUMMARY

I am a committed and ambitious professional that can quickly assimilate new ideas and concepts and demonstrate a logical and analytical approach to solving complex problems and issues. I am able to analyze code and engineer well-researched, cost-effective and responsive solutions.

Focused on customer satisfaction, I manage all aspects of the web development cycle, from concept to requirements definition, design, development, launch, maintenance, and user support. I enjoy the client-facing role and working closely with team members to produce high-quality deliverables. On a team, I help bring out a clearer sense of purpose and encourage more precise communication, transparency, and honesty, resulting in better team results and a higher sense of satisfaction for all involved.